A Guide to David E. Poisson Papers, 2006-2010
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
David E. Poisson Papers, 2006-2010
The Library of Virginia
50170
2 cubic feet (5 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of David E. Poisson, Arlington.
Biographical Information
David E. Poisson was born in Fall River, Massachusetts on 3 September 1951. He graduated from the University of Massachusetts, and he earned his doctorate and law degree at the University of Arizona. Poisson was employed as a lobbyist, and also gained legislative experience working in the offices of Senator Terry Stanford and Senator Richard Durbin. He also served as an adjunct faculty member in various universities in Virginia. Poisson was elected to represent the 32nd District in the Virginia House of Delegates, and served from 2006 to 2010. He was defeated for re-election in 2009. He practices law in Arlington, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Papers, 2006-2010, of David E. Poisson (b. 1951) of Arlington, Virginia, who represented the 32nd District in the Virginia House of Delegates from 2006 to 2010. Includes correspondence, legislative files, campaign literature, issue files, and other materials. Subjects of interest to Poisson that are represented in the collection include privatization of ABC stores, local school boards and grading systems, tollways, the state lottery, and veterans' issues.
Contents List
- Correspondence, 2006 (January-May). (Box 1, Folder 1-10)
- Correspondence, 2006 (May)-2008 (August). (Box 2, Folder 1-11)
- Correspondence, 2008 (September)-2010 (January). (Box 3, Folder 1-5)
- Campaign, 2006. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Campaign, 2007. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Campaign, 2009. (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Campaign Ephemera. (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Constitutional Amendment - School Boards. (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Dulles Greenway. (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Fair Grade. (Box 3, Folder 12)
- H.B. 61 - Gold Star License Plates. (Box 3, Folder 13)
- H. B. 99 - Forms of Ballots. (Box 3, Folder 14)
- H.B. 100 - Law Enforcement Officers Procedural Guarantee Act. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- H.B. 152 - Governmental Employee Associations. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- H.B. 153 - Solar Hot Water Systems. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- H.B. 164 - Compact Fluorescent Light Bulbs in State Buildings. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- H.B. 165 - Automatic Admission to Higher Education Institutions. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- H.B. 292 - State Lottery Administration Privatization. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- H.B. 293 - Weight Limits on Certain Roads. (Box 4, Folder 7)
- H.B. 611 - ABC Stores Privatization. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- H.B. 612 - Toll Payment Income Tax Credit. (Box 4, Folder 9)
- H.B. 613 - Licensure of Certain School Personnel. (Box 4, Folder 10)
- H.B. 614 - Definition of Public Charter Schools. (Box 4, Folder 11)
- H.B. 1250 - Flotation Devices for Children. (Box 4, Folder 12)
- H.B. 1588 - Insurance Coverage for Autism. (Box 4, Folder 13)
- H.B. 2314 - State Police Volunteer Chaplaincy Program. (Box 4, Folder 14)
- H.J.R. 43 - Online Higher Education Institution Study. (Box 4, Folder 15)
- H.J.R. 99 - Year-Round Colleges and Universities Study. (Box 4, Folder 16)
- H.J.R. 100 - Hospitality-Related Services Privatization Study. (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Hatrick, Edgar B.. (Box 4, Folder 18)
- I.D. Badge. (Box 4, Folder 19)
- License Plates. (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Our Lady of Hope Catholic Church. (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Lottery. (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
- "Report to the 32nd District". (Box 5, Folder 3)
- School Board. (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
- Veterans. (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Compact Disc - Cindy's Documents, 2008. (Box 5)
- Compact Disc - House of Delegates Files, 2006. (Box 5)
- DVD - Debate. (Box 5)
- Videotape - "Candidates on Demand," 26 September 2007. (Box 5)